Elmer Gertz Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Legal File, 1905-1992 (Box 13-300)
  - Professional, 1905-1992 (Box 18-300)
    - Students for a Democratic Society, Illinois Institute of Technology, Chicago, Ill.
      - Background information, 1963-1969, undated, (5 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1968, undated
    - Suarez v. Weaver
      - 1972
      - 1972-1974, (2 folders) (Box 248)
    - Szczesny v. Montgomery Ward, 1968-1971, undated, (4 folders)
    - Taylor v. Blakeslee-Division of Blake, 1988
    - Teague v. Leal, 1986-1987
    - Tele-Controls v. Ford Indus., 1966-1967, undated, (2 folders) (Box 249)
    - Terrell v. Clay
      - Background information, 1962-1969, undated, (5 folders)
      - Correspondence
        - 1965-1966, (3 folders)
        - 1966-1967, undated, (3 folders) (Box 250)
      - Court documents, 1965-1966, undated, (5 folders)
    - Togetherness Enters. v. License Appeal Comm'n
      - 1972, (2 folders)
      - 1972-1973, undated, (2 folders) (Box 251)
    - Torda, T. Paul, 1976-1978
    - Tovey v. Levy
      - Correspondence, 1946-1947
      - Court documents, 1947, undated
    - Tropic of Cancer
      - Background information
        - 1944-1962, (6 folders)
        - 1963-1965, undated, (5 folders) (Box 252)
      - Cases
        - Attorney General v. A Book Named Tropic of Cancer, 1961-1962
        - Big Table, Inc. v. Schroeder, 1960, undated
        - City of Chicago v. Compton, 1962, undated
        - City of Chicago v. Galis, 1961-1964 See also same container, City of Chicago v. Jenkins, and Container 253, City of Chicago v. Kaplan
        - City of Chicago v. Jenkins, 1961-1964 See also same container, City of Chicago v. Galis, and Container 253, City of Chicago v. Kaplan
        - City of Chicago v. Kaplan, 1959-1964 See also Container 252, City of Chicago v. Galis and City of Chicago v. Jenkins, (2 folders) (Box 253)
        - Grove Press v. Calissi, 1961-1963
        - Haiman v. Morris
          - Correspondence, 1961-1964, undated, (5 folders)
          - Court documents
            - 1961
            - 1961-1962, (7 folders) (Box 254)
            - 1962, (6 folders) (Box 255, Box 256)
            - 1963-1964, undated, (10 folders) (Box 257)
          - General, 1961-1964, undated (Box 258)
        - Lovitt v. Greenway, 1961
        - Pennsylvania v. Robin, 1961, undated
        - Ronsley v. Stanczak, 1962-1963, undated
        - United States v. Three Books Alleged by the Customs Auths. to be Obscene, 1961
        - Village of Maywood v. Penny, 1961-1962, undated
      - Correspondence
        - 1961-1962, (6 folders)
        - 1962-1963, (8 folders) (Box 259)
        - 1964-1965, undated, (4 folders) (Box 260)
      - Exhibits, 1961-1962, undated
      - Press
        - 1961-1962, (3 folders)
        - 1962-1964, (4 folders) (Box 261)
    - Union Carbide Corp. v. Ever-Ready, 1978, undated, (2 folders)
    - United States v. Montgomery Ward & Co., 1945
    - United States v. Pitasi
      - Background information
        - 1942-1973, undated, (2 folders)
        - Undated, (1 folder) (Box 262)
      - Correspondence, 1969-1973, undated, (2 folders)
      - Court documents, 1969-1971, undated, (2 folders)
    - United States v. Shlensky
      - Background information, 1963-1964, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1964-1969, undated, (2 folders)
      - Court documents, 1963-1964, undated
    - United States v. Teller (Box 263)
      - Background information
        - 1945-1966, (8 folders)
        - Undated, (1 folder); (5 folders) (Box 264)
      - Correspondence, 1956-1966, undated, (4 folders)
      - Court documents, 1959-1961, undated, (8 folders) (Box 265)
    - United States ex rel. Miller v. Pate (Box 266)
      - Background information, 1961-1970
      - Correspondence, 1970
      - Court documents, 1963-1965, undated, (6 folders)
    - Van Zandt v. Thompson, 1986-1988, undated, (7 folders) (Box 267)
    - Wagner v. Wiser (Box 268)
      - Background information, 1968-1973, undated
      - Correspondence, 1965-1973, undated
      - Court documents, 1964-1973, undated, (3 folders)
    - Walsh v. Shell Oil Co.
      - Background information, 1967-1970, undated, (2 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1962-1970, undated
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1968, undated
        - General, 1968-1969, undated, (3 folders)
    - Ware, Magnolia, 1966, undated (Box 269)
    - Warner v. Northern Trust Co.
      - Background information, 1947-1954, undated, (4 folders)
      - Correspondence, 1945-1954, undated, (4 folders)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1945
        - General, 1952-1954, undated, (5 folders) (Box 270)
    - Watson, Philip A., Million Dollar Round Table Foundation, 1957-1963, undated, (2 folders)
    - Watson v. Sparkman & Stephens, Inc.
      - Background information
        - Correspondence
          - 1964-1965, (2 folders)
          - 1965-1968, (3 folders) (Box 271)
        - General
          - 1961-1967, (5 folders)
          - 1968-1972, undated, (8 folders) (Box 272)
        - Plans and specifications (Box 273)
          - 1963-1964 See also Oversize, (6 folders)
          - 1965, undated See also Oversize, (2 folders) (Box 274)
      - Billing, 1968-1974, undated
      - Correspondence
        - 1965-1969, (6 folders)
        - 1970-1974, undated, (5 folders) (Box 275)
      - Court documents
        - Depositions
          - 1966-1967, (3 folders)
          - 1967-1968, (6 folders) (Box 276)
          - 1968, (6 folders) (Box 277)
          - 1968-1969, (2 folders) (Box 278)
        - Exhibits
          - 1964-1968, (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 279)
        - General
          - 1966-1974, (7 folders)
          - Undated, (4 folders) (Box 280)
    - Weintraub v. Scott
      - Background information
        - 1968-1970, (3 folders)
        - Undated, (1 folder) (Box 281)
      - Correspondence, 1970
      - Court documents, 1970, undated, (2 folders)
    - Weissbuch v. Governors State Univ., 1977-1982, undated, (2 folders)
    - West, Dorothy, 1966, undated
    - Wilson v. Indiana, 1966-1968, undated
    - Wisconsin v. I, A Woman, Part II
      - Background information, 1960-1972, undated, (4 folders)
      - Correspondence
        - 1969-1971, (2 folders)
        - 1971-1972 (Box 282)
      - Court documents, 1969-1972, undated, (5 folders)
    - Witherspoon, William W.
      - Cases
        - Illinois v. Witherspoon, 1960-1965, undated
        - United States ex rel. Witherspoon v. Ogilvie
          - 1959, (1 folder)
          - 1963-1965, undated, (5 folders) (Box 283)
        - Witherspoon v. Illinois
          - Supreme Court of Illinois
            - 1962-1965, (3 folders)
            - 1966-1969, undated, (2 folders) (Box 284)
          - United States Supreme Court
            - Background information
              - Death penalty polls, 1966-1968
              - General
                - 1946-1970, (5 folders)
                - Undated, (3 folders) (Box 285)
            - Correspondence
              - 1967-1969, (5 folders)
            - Court documents (Box 286)
              - 1967, (6 folders)
              - 1968, undated, (3 folders) (Box 287)
            - Press, 1968-1969, (3 folders)
      - Correspondence
        - 1965, (2 folders)
        - 1965-1969, 1979, (8 folders) (Box 288)
      - Executive clemency
        - Letters and petitions from the public, selected samples, 1965, (2 folders)
        - Petition, 1965, undated, (2 folders) (Box 289)
      - General, 1965-1969, undated
      - Press, 1964-1965, undated
    - Wright v. United States, 1964-1965, undated
    - Yap, Simeon
      - Background information, 1929-1965, undated
      - Correspondence, 1962-1967, (4 folders)
    - Young v. Stahelin (Box 290)
      - Background information
        - 1958-1962, (8 folders)
        - 1963-1968, (11 folders) (Box 291)
        - 1970-1974, (2 folders) (Box 292)
        - Undated, (7 folders) (Box 293)
      - Billing, 1972-1974
      - Correspondence
        - 1961-1965, (6 folders)
        - 1966-1974, undated, (10 folders) (Box 294)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits
          - 1965-1966
          - Undated (Box 295)
        - General
          - 1964-1967, (9 folders)
          - 1968-1971, undated, (6 folders) (Box 296)
    - Zeinfeld v. Hayes Freight Lines
      - Background information
        - American Carloading Co., 1956-1968
        - Bally Transportation Co., 1957
        - Broker, 1957
        - Colony Motor Transportation, 1956
        - General
          - 1955-1972, (5 folders)
          - Undated, (5 folders) (Box 297)
        - Gordy Freight Lines, 1955-1957, undated
        - Indianapolis Forwarding Co., 1957
        - Miller Transportation, 1955-1957
        - Mound City Forwarding, 1956-1957, undated
        - Penn-Dixie Lines, 1955-1957, undated, (2 folders)
        - Speedway, Inc., 1956
        - Tucker Freight Lines, undated (Box 298)
        - White Owl Express, 1957, undated, (2 folders)
      - Billing, 1972, undated
      - Correspondence
        - 1956-1967, (8 folders)
        - 1968-1972, undated, (3 folders) (Box 299)
      - Court documents
        - Exhibits, 1956-1971, undated, (2 folders)
        - General
          - 1958-1968, (6 folders)
          - 1969-1972, undated, (7 folders) (Box 300)
- Subject File, 1894, 1903-1990 (Box 300-380)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes of meetings, invitations, speeches, statements, writings, resolutions, background information, financial and legal papers, notes, newspaper clippings, and printed matter.
  Arrangement is alphabetical by name of person or organization, topic, or type of material.
  - Adelman, Abram E., 1958 (Box 300)
  - Adult Education Council of Greater Chicago, Chicago, Ill.
    - Carl Sandburg memorial tribute, 1967-1968, (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 301)
    - General
      - 1956-1961, (8 folders)
      - 1962-1967, (8 folders) (Box 302)
      - 1967-1971, (7 folders) (Box 303)
      - 1972, undated, (3 folders) (Box 304)
  - Advisory Committee to the Chief Justice of the Municipal Court of Chicago, 1949-1951, undated
  - Air pollution, 1963
  - Allied News Co., 1964, undated
  - American Friends of the Hebrew University, 1952-1960, (2 folders)
  - American Jewish Congress See also Container 5, same heading
    - 1955-1959, (2 folders)
    - 1959-1960, (7 folders) (Box 305)
    - 1960-1963, (7 folders) (Box 306)
    - 1963-1973, undated, (4 folders) (Box 307)
  - Anastaplo, George, 1965-1984, undated, (4 folders)
  - Andrews, Wayne, 1951-1973 See also Container 5, same heading
  - “A” miscellaneous, 1960-1978, undated, (4 folders) (Box 308)
  - Baldwin, James, 1965, (2 folders)
  - Brome, Vincent, 1929, 1956-1960
  - Bruce, Lenny, 1961-1966
  - “B” miscellaneous, 1956-1978, undated, (5 folders) (Box 309)
  - Capp, Jerome B., 1963-1967, undated
  - Carey Ordinance Committee, 1949, undated
  - Censorship, 1964-1966, undated, (3 folders)
  - Chi, 1952, undated (Box 310)
  - Chicago Bar Association
    - Civil Rights Committee
      - 1977-1979, (7 folders)
      - 1979-1980, (8 folders) (Box 311)
      - 1983-1985, undated, (5 folders) (Box 312)
    - Civil rights seminar, 1982-1983, undated
    - Committee on Legal Education
      - 1960-1967, (3 folders)
      - 1968-1973, undated, (5 folders) (Box 313)
    - Committee on Post War Problems, 1945-1952
    - Committee on Unauthorized Practice, 1951-1953, (2 folders)
  - Chicago Citizens Commission to Study the Disorders of Convention Week (Box 314)
    - Correspondence, 1968-1970, undated, (3 folders)
    - General
      - 1967-1969, (2 folders)
      - Undated, (3 folders) (Box 315)
    - Press, 1968-1969, undated, (2 folders)
    - Reports
      - 1968-1969, (2 folders)
      - Undated, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 316)
  - Chicago Committee on Emergency Aid to Packinghouse Workers Families, 1948, undated
  - Chicago Jewish Forum, 1946-1948, (2 folders)
  - Citizens Commission to Study the Events Relating to the April 27, 1968, Peace Demonstration See Containers 314-316, Chicago Citizens Commission to Study the Disorders of Convention Week
  - Civil liberties, 1964-1970
  - Civil rights, 1963-1969, undated, (2 folders)
  - Committee to Secure Justice for Morton Sobell, 1953-1967, undated, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 317)
  - Crandall, Allen, 1927-1949, undated, (2 folders)
  - “C” miscellaneous, 1964-1978, undated, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 318)
  - Daley, Richard M., 1989
  - Darrow, Clarence
    - Film, 1955-1960, undated
    - General
      - 1903-1937, 1953-1957 See also Oversize, (3 folders)
      - 1957, (6 folders) (Box 319)
      - 1957-1970, undated, (6 folders) (Box 320)
  - Death penalty
    - Correspondence
      - 1962-1973, (2 folders)
      - 1974-1983 (Box 321)
    - General
      - 1959-1975, (7 folders)
      - 1976-1983, undated, (9 folders) (Box 322)
  - Douglas, Melvyn, 1957-1971, (2 folders) (Box 323)
  - Dreier, Alvin W., 1968-1975, undated
  - “D” miscellaneous, 1955-1975, undated, (2 folders)
  - Einstein, Albert, Decalogue Society of Lawyers Award of Merit, 1954 See also Container 6, same heading
  - Eisenstein, Irving, 1965-1974
  - “E” miscellaneous, 1955-1978, undated, (3 folders)
  - Fail Safe, 1964 (Box 324)
  - Fink, Eli E., 1964-1977, undated See also Container 7, same heading
  - First Amendment Lawyers Association, Philadelphia, Pa., 1974-1984, (9 folders)
  - Fletcher, Bramwell, 1962-1968, undated
  - Friend, James, 1967-1975, undated, (3 folders) (Box 325)
  - “F” miscellaneous, 1961-1978, undated, (4 folders)
  - Galena, Ill., 1894, 1955-1956
  - Glickman, Bernard, 1966, 1972
  - Grove Press, 1964-1969, undated, (2 folders) (Box 326)
  - “G” miscellaneous, 1963-1977, undated, (5 folders)
  - Harris, Frank For additional material see Container 325, Friend, James; Containers 390-391, "The Best of Frank Harris;" Containers 410-416, Frank Harris; and Containers 454-455, Short Stories of Frank Harris
    - 1932-1948, (2 folders)
    - 1950-1967, undated, (10 folders) (Box 327)
  - Hodge, Orville, 1956, undated (Box 328)
  - Holyroyd, Michael, 1971
  - Housing
    - Chicago Mayor's Emergency Housing Committee, 1945-1947, undated, (5 folders)
    - Community Homes, Inc., 1946-1947, undated
    - Home and Community Planning Association
      - 1931-1946, (2 folders)
      - 1946-1947, (9 folders) (Box 329)
      - 1947-1952, undated, (10 folders) (Box 330)
      - Undated, (3 folders) (Box 331)
    - Public housing
      - 1935-1946, (9 folders)
      - 1946-1947, (10 folders) (Box 332)
      - 1947-1950, (11 folders) (Box 333)
      - 1951-1963, undated, (8 folders) (Box 334)
    - Residential Development Corp., 1947-1948, undated, (2 folders)
    - Restrictive covenants, 1944-1947, undated, (6 folders) (Box 335)
    - Veterans housing, 1945-1946, undated
  - Humphrey, Hubert H., 1968-1969, undated See also Container 8, same heading
  - “H” miscellaneous, 1957-1978, undated, (4 folders)
  - Illinois (Box 336)
    - Constitution For additional material see Container 354, Illinois initiative
      - Amendments, 1976
      - Referendum, 1970
    - Constitutional convention
      - Committee on Bill of Rights
        - General, 1970, undated, (4 folders)
        - Minutes, 1970, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 337)
        - Proposals, 1970, (2 folders)
        - Research material, 1970, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 338)
        - Testimony, 1970, undated
      - Correspondence
        - 1969, (2 folders)
        - 1970 (Box 339)
          - 2 Jan.-23 Mar., (7 folders)
          - 23 Mar.-14 June, (7 folders) (Box 340)
          - 15-22 June, (7 folders) (Box 341)
          - 22-23 June, (7 folders) (Box 342)
          - 23 June-7 July, (7 folders) (Box 343)
          - 7 July-30 Oct., (7 folders) (Box 344)
          - 2 Nov.-31 Dec., (2 folders) (Box 345)
          - Undated, (2 folders)
      - Delegate campaign
        - Correspondence
          - 1969
            - July-Aug., (2 folders)
            - Sept.-Dec., (7 folders) (Box 346)
          - Undated
        - Endorsements, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 347)
        - General, 1969, (6 folders); (1 folder) (Box 348)
        - Primary petition, 1969
      - Executive Article Committee, undated, (5 folders)
      - Fair housing, 1968-1970, undated, (3 folders) (Box 349)
      - General, 1970-1972, 1979, undated, (3 folders)
      - Press, 1969-1970, undated
      - Reconvening of the 1970 delegates, 1986-1987, undated, (2 folders) (Box 350)
      - Referendum
        - 1984-1988, (4 folders)
        - 1988, undated, (3 folders) (Box 351)
      - Reports, 1969-1970, undated, (4 folders)
      - Resolutions, 1970, undated
      - Speeches, statements, and testimonies, 1970, undated, (4 folders) (Box 352)
  - Illinois Coalition Against the Death Penalty
    - 1977-1982, (4 folders)
    - 1983-1985, undated, (5 folders) (Box 353)
  - Illinois Committee to Abolish Capital Punishment
    - 1964-1971, (4 folders)
    - Undated (Box 354)
  - Illinois Freedom to Read Committee, 1963-1967, undated, (2 folders)
  - Illinois initiative and the Lincoln amendment (proposals to amend the Illinois constitution), 1982, (3 folders)
  - Illinois State Bar Association, Individual Rights and Responsibilities Section
    - 1980-1982, (3 folders)
    - 1982-1984, undated, (6 folders) (Box 355)
  - Immunity matters, 1966
  - Indiana University Press, 1961-1975, undated
  - “I” miscellaneous, 1967-1978, undated
  - Jarke Sales Co., 1959-1967, undated, (2 folders) (Box 356)
  - Jewish history, 1964-1972, undated
  - Johnson, Jack A., 1969
  - “J” miscellaneous, 1964-1978, undated, (4 folders)
  - Kennedy, John F.
    - Assassination, 1964-1977, undated, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 357)
    - General, 1956-1960, undated
  - Kilty, Jerome, 1965-1967, undated
  - Klinger, Maurice, 1977
  - “K” miscellaneous, 1962-1978, (6 folders)
  - Lane, Mark, 1962-1968, undated, (2 folders)
  - Lefkovitz, David, 1954-1974, undated (Box 358)
  - Lehman, Herbert H., 1956, undated
  - Leighton, George N., 1954-1974, undated, (7 folders)
  - Library of Congress, 1954-1955, 1975-1978
  - Lincoln Memorial University Press, 1946-1951, undated
  - Lovitz, Gene See also Container 9, same heading; Container 408, “Death Row;” and Containers 451-454, Sandburg
    - 1968-1977, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 359)
  - Lund, Sister Candida, 1966-1975, undated
  - “L” miscellaneous, 1961-1979, (6 folders)
  - Maling, Arthur, 1980, (2 folders)
  - Maturity, Chicago, Ill., 1975-1982 (Box 360)
  - McCarthy, Eugene J., 1968-1975
  - McCuen, Charles, 1971-1972, 1985, undated
  - McGovern, George S., 1972, undated, (3 folders)
  - McWilliams, Carey See also Container 9, same heading
    - 1929-1968, (6 folders)
    - Undated, (3 folders) (Box 361)
  - Miller, Henry, 1944-1964, undated For additional material see Containers 251-261, Tropic of Cancer and Containers 424-427, Henry Miller, (8 folders)
  - Miscellaneous, 1975-1977, undated
  - Mitchell, Stephen A., 1956-1957
  - “M” miscellaneous, 1964-1984, undated, (5 folders) (Box 362)
  - NAACP Legal Defense Fund Capital Punishment Project, 1968-1971, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 363)
  - Niver, Joseph, 1930, 1969, undated
  - Notes and jottings, undated
  - “N” miscellaneous, 1965-1978, (5 folders)
  - Obscenity, 1936, 1956-1976, undated, (6 folders) (Box 364)
  - “O” miscellaneous, 1966-1976, undated
  - Pearson, Hesketh, 1920-1959, undated
  - Percy, Charles H., 1969-1975, undated
  - Peters, Muriel
    - Correspondence
      - 1944-1956, (1 folder)
      - 1957-1974, (8 folders) (Box 365)
      - 1975-1988, undated, (1 folder) (Box 366)
    - Miscellaneous, 1944-1945, 1966-1975, undated
    - Writings, 1946-1950, 1967-1988, undated
  - Petrakis, Harry Mark, 1966-1974, undated, (3 folders)
  - Plumbing contractors, 1946-1950, (3 folders)
  - Political file, 1955-1973, undated, (3 folders)
  - Pollackrosten, Peter, 1972-1978, undated (Box 367)
  - Press, 1949-1988, undated, (4 folders)
  - Pullar, Philippa, 1971-1975
  - “P” miscellaneous, 1964-1978, (5 folders)
  - Race relations, 1943-1947, undated, (2 folders) (Box 368)
  - Remer, Theodore G., 1965-1969, undated, (2 folders)
  - Roosevelt University, Chicago, Ill. See also Container 11, same heading
    - 1945-1960, (4 folders)
    - 1960-1970, undated, (6 folders) (Box 369)
  - Ryan, William F.
    - 1973-1981, (3 folders)
    - 1982-1990, undated, (2 folders) (Box 370)
  - “R” miscellaneous, 1954-1984, undated, (6 folders)
  - Sandburg, Carl, 1968-1978 See also Container 11, same heading; and for additional material see Containers 451-454, Sandburg, (2 folders)
  - Saperstein, Esther, 1960-1969, undated See also Container 11, same heading; for additional material see Container 6, Douglas, Paul Howard (Box 371)
  - School, prayer in, 1955-1962, undated, (3 folders)
  - Schwartz, Edward P. See also Container 11, same heading
    - 1964-1966, (4 folders)
    - 1966-1978, undated, (7 folders) (Box 372)
  - Secretary of State [Illinois] Advisory Committee on Distribution of Government Information
    - Cases and opinions, 1952-1982
    - General
      - 1981
      - 1982-1983, undated, (8 folders) (Box 373)
    - Information released, 1982 (Box 374)
    - Need for and uses of information, 1977-1981
    - Sale of information, 1979-1982
    - Statutes, undated
  - Sentinel, 1961-1962
  - Shaw, Bernard, 1954-1978, undated See also Container 382, same heading, (5 folders)
  - Siegel, Barbara, 1963-1964
  - Silbert, Samuel H., 1963-1965, undated
  - Simon, Paul, 1968-1988, undated, (7 folders) (Box 375)
  - Sobell, Morton, 1967-1969
  - Société de Courtage International de Livres et Objects d'art (SCILOA)
  - Stevenson, Adlai E. (1900-1965)
    - 1951-1952, (2 folders)
    - 1952-1972, undated, (5 folders) (Box 376)
  - “S” miscellaneous, 1952-1978, undated, (4 folders); (5 folders) (Box 377)
  - Tesla, Nikola
    - 1926-1959, (4 folders)
    - 1960-1975, undated, (4 folders) (Box 378)
  - Truman, Harry S., 1955-1962, 1974-1977, undated
  - Turn Towards Peace, 1965-1966
  - “T” miscellaneous, 1962-1977, (2 folders)
  - University of Chicago, Chicago, Ill.
    - 1951-1960, (4 folders)
    - 1960-1978, undated, (6 folders) (Box 379)
  - “U” miscellaneous, 1965-1977
  - Viereck, Peter Robert Edwin, 1941-1968, undated, (3 folders)
  - “V” miscellaneous, 1965-1977, undated
  - Ward, Francis, 1966-1968, undated
  - Wawszkienicz, Edward J., 1982-1983 (Box 380)
  - Weyand, Ruth, 1950-1956
  - “W” miscellaneous, 1946-1977, (6 folders)
  - Yates, Sidney R., 1965-1977, 1988
  - “Y” miscellaneous, 1969-1977, undated
  - Zesmer, David, 1976-1978, undated
  - “Z” miscellaneous, 1965-1977, undated
- Speeches and Writings File, 1888-1990 (Box 381-465)
  - Speech File, 1947-1988 (Box 381-383)
    Correspondence, memoranda, speeches, research material, announcements and programs, newspaper clippings, and printed matter.
    Arrangement is by type of material and therein chronological.
    - Announcements and programs, 1947-1988, undated, (2 folders) (Box 381)
    - Correspondence, 1952, 1962-1970, (5 folders)
    - Miscellany, 1964-1969, undated
    - Press, 1952-1985, undated, (3 folders) (Box 382)
    - Research material
      - Obscenity, 1971-1974, undated
      - Shaw, Bernard, 1972, undated See also Container 374, same heading
    - Speeches
      - 1948-1982, (6 folders)
      - 1983-1988, undated, (5 folders) (Box 383)
  - Writings, 1888-1990 (Box 383-465)
    Correspondence, memoranda, handwritten drafts and typescripts of books, articles, reviews, research material, interviews, pamphlets, prefaces to books, poetry, notes, outlines, newspaper clippings, and printed matter. Includes one reel of microfilm* of Sigmund Freud-George Sylvester Viereck correspondence, the originals of which are not in the collection.